# **Sara Eilenstine**

Software Engineer

🌎 github.com/cattelia 📞 (541) 304-9487 🛅 linkedin.com/in/saraeilenstine 🕈 Lynnwood, WA

# **Professional Summary:**

I am a software engineer with program management and leadership experience and a focus on application, process, and operational automation. Having both back-end and front-end experience ranging from my Internship with Symantec with on-premise database migration, collegiate studies, to Bootcamps I have taken more recently combined with my program management, automation, leadership, and stakeholder communications skills, I bring a unique perspective and passion for building clean, minimalist tools and applications that both companies and customers need, trust, and want.

## Professional Experience [Current/Relevant]

# Card Kingdom - Monroe, WA

Inventory Supervisor Mar 2024 - Present

- Lead, train and support a team of 12 with their personal goals and our daily output is 60% higher compared to other teams.
- Designed, planned and got stakeholder buy-in for new product release flow, which results in 30% higher fulfillment rates.

Operation Specialist Mar 2023 – Mar 2024

## Keepe - Seattle, WA

Program Manager Sep 2022 – Mar 2023

- Solely developed the *Parts Department* with a team of 6 which reduced product loss by 90% and secured a 10% flat cost reduction on all purchases by negotiating and winning contracts with part suppliers through technical support in the analysis, evaluation of options, and solutions of business needs.
- The liaison between the development team, management, partner relations, customers who use the product, and vendors.
- Delivered an automated return system that part suppliers developed to integrate with CRMs and product purchasing cycle.
- Communicate with audiences of varying levels demonstrating solid business oral, writing and presentation skills.
- Integrated automations using Zapier, Streak CRM, and Google Suite to track and maintain data logs.

Operations Acceleration Feb 2022 – Sept 2022

#### Symantec - Springfield, OR

Site Reliability Engineer Intern

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

- Built and deployed an automated security scanning tool using Qualys and Powershell to run security scans on spun-up host environments orchestrated by Jenkins inside of Azure to secure and validate it for use.
- Other tasks included servicing internal network traffic requests, draft technical docs, validate secure route tables, load-balancing simulations and confirming connections for internal users.

## University of Oregon - Eugene, OR

Tier III – Technology Escalation Specialist

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017

- Train and mentor over 6 Tier I/II peers in internal processes, technical troubleshooting, networking protocols, PII/PCI/HIPPA compliance, SaaS platforms, technical documentation, and more.
- Excellent communication skills that allow me to translate and break down complex concepts for non-technical people.

Tier II - Technology Escalation Specialist

Feb 2016 - Sep 2016

- Handled increasingly escalated cases as well as customer remediation for conflicts or technical issues.

Tier I - Technology Escalation Specialist

Aug 2015 - Feb 2016

#### **Education & Certificates**

Boot.dev (2024 - present) - Object Oriented Programing, Shells & Terminals, Learn Git, Learn Python, Functional Programming FreeCodeCamp (2023 - 2024) - Data Analysis with Python, Scientific Computing with Python, Relational Database, Quality Assurance University of Oregon - Bachelor of Arts - BA, Spanish & Computer Science (2020)

#### **Skills**

Programming: Python, Go, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

Tech Stack: Github, Visual Studio Code (IDE), Terminal, Linux, Git, Docker, CI/CD / Kanban methodologies

Tools: Slack, Trello, Jira (Ticketing), Confluence (Technical Documentation), Notion

Soft Skills: I'm easy to work with, Communication, Continuous Learning/Improvement, Planning, Adaptability, Trust, Savvy